


export const QuizData = [
    {
        id: 0 , 
        category:"مبادئ المحاسبه (1)",
        difficulty:"easy",
        question: `Which of the following is not a step in the accounting process ?`,
        options: [`identification`, `verification` ,`recording`, `communication`],
        answer: `verification`
    },

    {
        id: 1,
        category:"مبادئ المحاسبه (1)",
        difficulty: "medium",
        question: `Ethics are the standards of conduct by which one's actions are judged as`,
        options: [`fair or unfair`, `Zarqa`, `all of these`, `honest or dishonest`],
        answer: `all of these`
    },

    {
        id: 2,
        category:"مبادئ المحاسبه (1)",
        difficulty: "hard",
        question: `The three types of business entities are ?`,     
        options: [`financial, manufacturing, and service companies`, `proprietorships, partnerships, and large businesses`, `proprietorships, partnerships, and corporations `, `proprietorships, small businesses, and partnerships`],
        answer: `proprietorships, partnerships, and corporations`
    },

    {
        id: 3,
        category: "المحاسبة الادارية",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: `Managerial accounting:`,
        options: [`is limited to cost data`, `pertains to the entity as a whole and is highly`, `is governed by generally accepted accounting`, `places emphasis on special-purpose information`],
        answer: `places emphasis on special-purpose information`
    },

    {
        id: 4,
        category: "المحاسبة الادارية",
        difficulty: "medium",
        question: "A cost of goods manufactured schedule shows beginning and ending inventories for:",
        options: [`raw materials, work in process, and finished goods`, `raw materials only`, `work in process only`, `raw materials and work in process only .`],
        answer: `raw materials and work in process only .`
    },

    {
        id: 5,
        category: "المحاسبة الادارية",
        difficulty: "medium",
        question: `Gammil Company has beginning and ending raw materials inventories of $96,000 and $120,000, respectively. If direct materials used were $440,000, what was the cost of raw materials purchased?`,
        options: [`$464,000`, `416,000`, `470,000` , `440,000`],
        answer: `$464,000`
    },
    // {
    //     id: 6 , 
    //     category:"Accounting Principles(1)",
    //     difficulty: "esay",
    //     question: `Which of the following is not a step in the accounting process ?`,
    //     options: [`identification`, `verification` ,`recording`, `communication`],
    //     answer: `verification`
    // },

    {
        id: 7,
        category:"مبادئ المحاسبه (1)",
        difficulty: "medium",
        question: `Ethics are the standards of conduct by which one's actions are judged as`,
        options: [`fair or unfair`, `Zarqa`, `all of these`, `honest or dishonest`],
        answer: `all of these`
    },

    {
        id: 8,
        category:"مبادئ المحاسبه (1)",
        difficulty: "hard",
        question: `The three types of business entities are ?`,     
        options: [`financial, manufacturing, and service companies`, `proprietorships, partnerships, and large businesses`, `  proprietorships, partnerships, and corporations `, `proprietorships, small businesses, and partnerships`],
        answer: ` proprietorships, partnerships, and corporations`
    },

    {
        id: 9,
        category: "المحاسبة الادارية",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: `The management of an organization performs several broad functions. They are:`,
        options: [`planning, directing, and selling`, `planning, directing, and controlling`, `planning, manufacturing, and controlling.`,`directing, manufacturing, and controlling.`],
        answer: `planning, directing, and controlling`
    },


    {
        id: 9,
        category: "المحاسبة الادارية",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: `Molina Company has beginning and ending work in process inventories of $130,000 and $145,000 respectively. If total manufacturing costs are $650,000, what is the total cost of goods manufactured?`,
        options: [`$780,000`, `$780,000`, `$635,000`,`$665,000`],
        answer: `$635,000`
    },

    
    {
        id: 10,
        category: "المحاسبة الادارية",
        difficulty: "medium",
        question: "A cost of goods manufactured schedule shows beginning and ending inventories for:",
        options: [`raw materials, work in process, and finished goods`, `raw materials only`, `work in process only`, `raw materials and work in process only`],
        answer: `raw materials and work in process only .`
    },
    
    {
        id: 10,
        category: "المحاسبة الادارية",
        difficulty: "medium",
        question: "Which of the following costs are classified as a period cost?",
        options: [`Wages paid to a factory custodian`, `Wages paid to a production department supervisor`, `Wages paid to a cost accounting department supervisor`, `Wages paid to an assembly worker`],
        answer: `Wages paid to a cost accounting department supervisor`
    },

    {
        id: 11,
        category: "المحاسبة الادارية",
        difficulty: "medium",
        question: `Barton Company has beginning work in process inventory of $144,000 and total manufacturing costs of $686,000. If cost of goods manufactured is $640,000, what is the cost of the ending work in process inventory?`,
        options: [`$190,000`, `$210,000`, `$198,000` , `$200,000`],
        answer: `$190,000`
    },

    {
        id: 11,
        category: "المحاسبة الادارية",
        difficulty: "hard",
        question: `Gammil Company has beginning and ending raw materials inventories of $96,000 and $120,000, respectively. If direct materials used were $440,000, what was the cost of raw materials purchased?`,
        options: [`$464,000`, `416,000`, `470,000` , `440,000`],
        answer: `$464,000`
    },

    {
        id: 11,
        category: "المحاسبة الادارية",
        difficulty: "hard",
        question: `Edmiston Company reported the following year-end information: beginning work in process inventory, $80,000; cost of goods manufactured, $780,000; beginning finished goods inventory, $50,000; ending work in process inventory, $70,000; and ending finished goods inventory, $40,000. How much is Edmiston’s cost of goods sold for the year?`,
        options: [`$780,000`, `$790,000`, `$770,000` , `$800,000`],
        answer: `$790,000`
    },


    {
        id: 12,
        category: "المحاسبة الادارية",
        difficulty: "hard",
        question: `Marshall Company had actual sales of $600,0000 when break-even sales were $420,000. what is the margin of safety ratio ?`,
        options: [`25%`, `30%`, `33%` , `45%`],
        answer: `30%`
    },

    {
        id: 11,
        category: "المحاسبة الادارية",
        difficulty: "hard",
        question: `After passage of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act:`,
        options: [`reports prepared by managerial accountants must by audited by CPAs`, `CEOs and CFOs must certify that financial statements give a fair presentation of the company’s operating results`, `the audit committee, rather than top management, is responsible for the company’s financial statements` , `reports prepared by managerial accountants must comply with generally accepted accounting principles (GAAP)`],
        answer: `CEOs and CFOs must certify that financial statements give a fair presentation of the company’s operating results`
    },


    {
        id: 11,
        category: "المحاسبة الادارية",
        difficulty: "hard",
        question: `For the year, Redder Company has cost of goods manufactured of $600,000, beginning finished goods inventory of $200,000, and ending finished goods inventory of $250,000. The cost of goods sold is:`,
        options: [`$550,000`, `$500,000` , `$600,000` , `455,000`],
        answer: `$550,000`
    },

    
    {
        id: 12,
        category: "نظرية المحاسبة",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: ` ......  هي ليست مجموعة من القوانين الجامدة`,
        options: [`الاساليب والطرق المحاسبية `, `المبادئ المحاسبية`, `القروض المحاسبية ` , `التعريفات المحاسبية `],
        answer: `المبادئ المحاسبية`
    },

    {
        id: 13 ,
        category: "نظرية المحاسبة",
        difficulty: "medium",
        question: ` : يدعو الى التركيز على مفهوم الرقابة الفعالة على الموارد الاقتصادية هم من يطلق عليهم`,
        options: [`الادارة  `, ` المالك في المنشأة الفردية `, `أ + ب` , `غير ذلك `],
        answer: `أ + ب`
    },

    {
        id: 14,
        category: "نظرية المحاسبة",
        difficulty: "hard",
        question: ` : مخرجات النظام المحاسبي هي `,
        options: [`هي وسائل المعالجة`, `هي المعلومات`, `المستندات ` , `البيانات`],
        answer: `هي المعلومات`
    },

    {
        id: 15,
        category: "تنظيم الاسرة والمجتمع",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: `: من السنة المستحبة أن`,
        options: [`يخفى الزواج وتظهر الخطبة`, `اظهار الخطبة وحدها`, `اخفاء الزواج وحده`, `اظهار الزواج واخفاء الخطبة`],
        answer: `اظهار الزواج واخفاء الخطبة`
    },

    {
        id: 16,
        category: "تنظيم الاسرة والمجتمع",
        difficulty: "medium",
        question: `: اخفاء الوعد بالخطبة دون سبب أو مبرر مشروع يكون`,
        options: [`جائز ديانة وقضاء`,`حرام قضاء `,`حرام ديانة`,`جميع ما ذكر`],
        answer: `حرام ديانة`
    },

    {
        id: 17,
        category: "تنظيم الاسرة والمجتمع",
        difficulty: "hard",
        question: `الاهلية في العاقدين في الزواج من شروط`,
        options: [` الانعقاد `, `  الصحة   `, `  الننفاذ  ` , ` اللزوم `],
        answer: ` اللزوم `
    },

    {
        id: 18,
        category: "مبادئ الاقتصاد الجزئي",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: `when the price is below equilibrium level, there will be :  `,
        options: [`Equilibrium leve`, `Excess demand`, `Excess supply` , `Excess in both & demand`],
        answer: `Excess demand`
    },

    {
        id: 19,
        category: "مبادئ الاقتصاد الجزئي",
        difficulty: "medium",
        question: `The which we forget, or give up , when we make a choice or decision is called`,
        options: [`total cose`, `marginal cose`, `real cost` , `opportunity cost`],
        answer: `opportunity cost`
    },

    {
        id: 20,
        category: "مبادئ الاقتصاد الجزئي",
        difficulty: "hard",
        question: `Economists use the phrase ceteris paribus to express the assumption`,
        options: [`All else equal.`, `everything affect everything else.`, `scarcity is a fact of life.` , `there is no such thing as a free lunch. `],
        answer: `All else equal.`
    },


    {
        id: 21,
        category: "نظم المعلومات المحاسبية (2)",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: `The American Accounting Association has formulated a general definition of auditing.  What is not a characteristic of this general definition? `,
        options: [`Auditing is a systematic process.`, `Auditors are responsible for objectively obtaining and evaluating evidence regarding assertions about economic actions and events. `, `Auditors are responsible for financial management and the investment of corporate assets. ` , `Auditors are responsible for communicating the results of audits to interested users.`],
        answer: `Auditors are responsible for financial management and the investment of corporate assets. `
    },

    {
        id: 22,
        category: "نظم المعلومات المحاسبية (2)",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: `Which characteristics below is not a characteristic of auditing? `,
        options: [`evidence collection .`, `establishing audit criteria .`, `objectivity .` , `systems development .`],
        answer: `objectivity .`
    },
    
    {
        id: 23,
        category: "نظم المعلومات المحاسبية (2)",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: `Auditing involves the `,
        options: [`collection, review, and documentation of audit evidence`, `planning and verification of economic events`, `collection of audit evidence and approval of economic events` , `testing, documentation, and certification of audit evidence`],
        answer: `collection, review, and documentation of audit evidence`
    },

    {
        id: 24,
        category: "نظم المعلومات المحاسبية (2)",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: `The purpose of an internal audit is `,
        options: [`a)	to evaluate the adequacy and effectiveness of company's internal controls.`, `b)	to determine the extent to which assigned responsibilities are actually carried out.`, `c)	to collect evidence on whether the company is continuing as a going concern. ` , `d)	A and B only `],
        answer: `b)	to determine the extent to which assigned responsibilities are actually carried out.`
    },
    
    {
        id: 25,
        category: "نظم المعلومات المحاسبية (2)",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: `The type of audit in which the primary responsibility of the auditors is the management of the organization is `,
        options: [`an external audit`, `a governmental audit`, `an internal audit`, `a public audits`],
        answer: `an internal audit`
    },

    {
        id: 25,
        category: "نظم المعلومات المحاسبية (2)",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: `The scope of a(n) __________ audit encompasses all aspects of information systems management`,
        options: [`operational`, `information systems`, `financial`, `internal control`],
        answer: `operational`
    },
    
    {
        id: 26,
        category: "نظم المعلومات المحاسبية (2)",
        difficulty: "medium",
        question: `What is not a typical responsibility of an internal auditor?`,
        options: [`helping management to improve organizational effectiveness`, `assisting in the design and implementation of an AIS `, `preparation of the company's financial statements`, `implementing and monitoring of internal controls`],
        answer: `preparation of the company's financial statements`
    },

    {
        id: 27,
        category: "نظم المعلومات المحاسبية (2)",
        difficulty: "medium",
        question: `The __________ audit examines the reliability and integrity of accounting records.`,
        options: [`financial`, `informational`, `information systems`, `operational`],
        answer: `financial`
    },
    
    {
        id: 28,
        category: "نظم المعلومات المحاسبية (2)",
        difficulty: "medium",
        question: `The __________ audit examines the reliability and integrity of accounting records.`,
        options: [`financial`, `informational`, `information systems`, `operational`],
        answer: `financial`
    },
    
    {
        id: 29,
        category: "نظم المعلومات المحاسبية (2)",
        difficulty: "medium",
        question: `The __________ audit reviews the general and application controls of an AIS to assess its compliance with internal control policies and procedures and its effectiveness in safeguarding assets.`,
        options: [`financial`, `information systems`, `management`, `internal control`],
        answer: `information systems`
    },
    
    {
        id: 30,
        category: "نظم المعلومات المحاسبية (2)",
        difficulty: "medium",
        question: `The __________ audit is concerned with the economical and efficient use of resources and the accomplishment of established goals and objectives.`,
        options: [`financial`, `information`, `information systems`, `operational`],
        answer: `information`
    },
    
    {
        id: 31,
        category: "نظم المعلومات المحاسبية (2)",
        difficulty: "hard",
        question: `The Institute of Internal Auditors (IIA) has established five audit scope standards that outline the internal auditor's responsibilities.  Which standard below deals with the principles of reliability and integrity? `,
        options: [`determining whether the systems are designed to comply with operating and reporting policies`, `review of how assets are safeguarded and verification of their existence as appropriate`, `review of company operations and programs to determine whether they are being carried out as planned`, `review of operating and financial information and how it is identified, measured, classified, and reported`],
        answer: `review of operating and financial information and how it is identified, measured, classified, and reported`
    },
    
    {
        id: 32,
        category: "نظم المعلومات المحاسبية (2)",
        difficulty: "hard",
        question: `Much of the effort spent in an audit entails the collection of evidence.  Verifying the accuracy of certain information, often through communication with certain third parties, is known in the language of the auditor a`,
        options: [`reperformance`, `confirmation`, `substantiation`, `documentation`],
        answer: `confirmation`
    },
    
    {
        id: 33,
        category: "نظم المعلومات المحاسبية (2)",
        difficulty: "hard",
        question: `To document the review of source data controls, an auditor may use`,
        options: [`an input control matrix`, `test data processing`, `computer audit software`, `analysis of program logic`],
        answer: `an input control matrix`
    },
    
    {
        id: 34,
        category: "نظم المعلومات المحاسبية (2)",
        difficulty: "hard",
        question: `In the __________ stage of an operational audit, the auditor measures the actual system against an ideal standard`,
        options: [`evidence collection`, `evidence evaluation`, `testing`, `internal control`],
        answer: `evidence evaluation`
    },
    
    {
        id: 35,
        category: "نظم المعلومات المحاسبية (2)",
        difficulty: "hard",
        question: `One function of CAS is to review data files to retrieve records meeting a specified criteria.  What is this function called?`,
        options: [`reformatting`, `file processing`, `data analysis`, `data selection`],
        answer: `data selection`
    },
    
    
    {
        id: 36,
        category: "تدقيق انظمة المعلومات المحاسبية",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: `A foreign key imposes a specific kind of integrity to related tables. What is the name of this integrity?`,
        options: [`Schema`, `Referential`, `Independence`, `Data` ,`None of the above`],
        answer: `Referential`
    },
    
    {
        id: 37,
        category: "تدقيق انظمة المعلومات المحاسبية",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: `What are the benefits associated with database technology?`,
        options: [`Data sharing` , `Referential` , `Data integration`, `Data independence`, `Answers #1 and #2 only`, `Answers #1, #2, and #3`],
        answer: `Answers #1, #2, and #3`
    },
    
    {
        id: 38,
        category: "تدقيق انظمة المعلومات المحاسبية",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: `Which of the following provides the low-level view of the database?`,
        options: [`Conceptual-level schema`, `External-level schema`, `The internal-level schema`, `None of the above`],
        answer: `The internal-level schema`
    },
    
    {
        id: 39,
        category: "تدقيق انظمة المعلومات المحاسبية",
        difficulty: "easy",
        question: `This type of key is used to link rows from one table to the rows in another table`,
        options: [`Primary key`, `Foreign key`, `Encryption key`, `Public key`],
        answer: `Foreign key`
    },
    
    {
        id: 40,
        category: "تدقيق انظمة المعلومات المحاسبية",
        difficulty: "medium", 
        question: `Which method of gathering business intelligence uses sophisticated statistical analysis and neural networks to aid in decision making?`,
        options: [`Data Warehousing`, `Semantic data modeling`, `Data mining`, `None of the above.`],
        answer: `Data mining`
    },
    
    {
        id: 41,
        category: "تدقيق انظمة المعلومات المحاسبية",
        difficulty: "medium", 
        question: `Which of the following cannot be blank (null)?`,
        options: [`Foreign key`, `Secondary key`, `Connecting key`, `Primary key` , `None of the above can be null.` , `Two of the above cannot be null.`],
        answer: `Primary key`
    },
    
    {
        id: 42,
        category: "تدقيق انظمة المعلومات المحاسبية",
        difficulty: "medium", 
        question: `When the same, non-key, data element is stored multiple times in table it creates an anomaly known as the:`,
        options: [`Delete Anomaly.`, `Update Anomaly.`, `Insert Anomaly.`, `None of the above.` , `None of the above can be null.` , `Two of the above cannot be null.`],
        answer: `Update Anomaly.`
    },
    
    {
        id: 43,
        category: "تدقيق انظمة المعلومات المحاسبية",
        difficulty: "medium", 
        question: `Which of the following are requirements of a relational database?`,
        options: [`All nonkey (primary and foreign) attributes must describe a quality of the item identified by the primary key.`, `All of the above.`, `Foreign keys (if not empty) must be a primary key in another table.`, `None of the above.` , `None of the above can be null.` , `Primary keys cannot be null or empty.`],
        answer: `All of the above.`
    },


    {
        id: 44,
        category: "تدقيق انظمة المعلومات المحاسبية",
        difficulty: "hard", 
        question: `When a non-null value for the primary key indicates that a specific object exists and can be identified by reference to its primary key value, it is referred to as`,
        options: [`the referential integrity rule.`, `the relational database rule.`, `the entity integrity rule.`, `None of the above.`],
        answer: `the entity integrity rule.`
    },



    {
        id: 45,
        category: "تدقيق انظمة المعلومات المحاسبية",
        difficulty: "hard", 
        question: `What is (are) the component(s) of a data dictionary?`,
        options: [`Field length`, `Field type`, `Authorized users`, `Data location` , `Answers #1, #2, and #3 are correct.`],
        answer: `Answers #1, #2, and #3 are correct.`
    },
    
    {
        id: 46,
        category: "تدقيق انظمة المعلومات المحاسبية",
        difficulty: "hard", 
        question: `"Get me the date attribute of the third tuple in the sales order relation." What is being requested?`,
        options: [`The person wants the value in the date field of the third table that is related to sales order.`, `The person wants the value in the date field of the third sales order that is related to the sales order item table.`, `The person wants the value in the date field in the third row of the sales order item table`, `The person wants the value in the date field of the third record in the sales order table.` , `None of the above.`],
        answer: `The person wants the value in the date field of the third record in the sales order table.`
    },
    
    {
        id: 47,
        category: "تدقيق انظمة المعلومات المحاسبية",
        difficulty: "hard", 
        question: `Data manipulation language is used to do which of the following?`,
        options: [`Updating the database`, `Creating the database`, `Querying the database`, `All of the above`],
        answer: `Updating the database`
    },
    
    {
        id: 48,
        category: "تحليل وتصميم النظم المحاسبية",
        difficulty: "easy", 
        question: `Database design includes all of the following steps except:`,
        options: [`systems analysis.`, `conceptual design.`, `Resource Allocation`, `None of the above.` , `physical design.`],
        answer: `Resource Allocation`
    },
    
    {
        id: 49,
        category: "تحليل وتصميم النظم المحاسبية",
        difficulty: "easy", 
        question: `Accountants are typically involved in all of the following database design steps except:`,
        options: [`designing the data dictionary.`, `specifying internal controls.`, `evaluate project feasibility.`, `managing the design staff.` , `testing the accuracy of the new database.` , `developing logical schemas.`],
        answer: `managing the design staff.`
    },
    
    
    {
        id: 50,
        category: "تحليل وتصميم النظم المحاسبية",
        difficulty: "easy", 
        question: `Cardinalities can define:`,
        options: [`How many sales transactions are associated with a customer.`, `The minimum number of customers that must be associated with a transaction.`, `How many customers are associated with each transaction.`, `The maximum number of customers that may be associated with a transaction.` , `All of the above.` , `None of the above.`],
        answer: `The minimum number of customers that must be associated with a transaction.`
    },
    

    {
        id: 51,
        category: "تحليل وتصميم النظم المحاسبية",
        difficulty: "easy", 
        question: `Which of the following statements about the REA data model is NOT true?`,
        options: [`The REA data model focuses on the business semantics underlying an organization's value-chain activities.`, `The REA data model was developed specifically for use in designing accounting information systems.`, `The REA model provides guidance for database design by identifying what entities should be included and by prescribing how to structure relationships among those entities.`, `The REA model provides guidance for database design by identifying what entities should be included and by prescribing how to structure relationships among those entities.` , `REA data models are usually depicted in the form of Data Flow Diagrams diagrams.`],
        answer: `REA data models are usually depicted in the form of Data Flow Diagrams diagrams.`
    },
    
    {
        id: 52,
        category: "تحليل وتصميم النظم المحاسبية",
        difficulty: "medium", 
        question: `The essential feature(s) of the REA template include the following:`,
        options: [`each event is linked to at least one other event`, `each event is linked to at least one resource that it affects.`, `each event is linked to at least two participating agents.`, `All of the above.` , `None of the above.`],
        answer: `All of the above.`
    },
    
    {
        id: 53,
        category: "تحليل وتصميم النظم المحاسبية",
        difficulty: "medium", 
        question: `A many to many relationship in an REA model would indicate which of the following is true?`,
        options: [`Each row in two linked tables must be associated to every other row in the tables.`, `A single row in one table may be associated with many rows in another linked table and a single row in the linked table may be associated with many rows in the first table.`, `each event is linked to at least two participating agents.`, `A single row in one table is associated with one and only one row in another linked table` , `A single row in one table must be associated with many rows in another linked table and a single row in the linked table must be associated with many rows in the first table`],
        answer: `A single row in one table may be associated with many rows in another linked table and a single row in the linked table may be associated with many rows in the first table.`
    },
    
    {
        id: 54,
        category: "تحليل وتصميم النظم المحاسبية",
        difficulty: "medium", 
        question: `Which of the following is NOT correct under the REA model for the production cycle?`,
        options: [`Inventory is a "get"`, `Raw materials are a "give"`, `Employee time is a "give"`, `Machinery is a "get"`],
        answer: `Machinery is a "get"`
    },
    

    {
        id: 55,
        category: "تحليل وتصميم النظم المحاسبية",
        difficulty: "medium", 
        question: `Developing an REA diagram for a specific transaction cycle requires which step(s)?`,
        options: [`Indentify the specific employees associated with each REA relationship.`, `Determine the cardinalities of each relationship.`, `Identify the events about which management wants to collect information.`, `Both Answer #1 and Answer #2 are correct.` , `None of the above are correct.`],
        answer: `Both Answer #1 and Answer #2 are correct.`
    },
    

    {
        id: 56,
        category: "تحليل وتصميم النظم المحاسبية",
        difficulty: "hard", 
        question: `Which of the following statements or examples explains the meaning of a minimum cardinality of 1:`,
        options: [`Means that each instance of that entity must be linked to at least one instance of the other entity participating in that relationship.`, `Means that an instance of the entity on this side of the relationship need not be linked to any specific instances of the other entity.`, `Indicates a relationship between a sales relationship and a particular customer.` , `None of the above.`],
        answer: `Means that each instance of that entity must be linked to at least one instance of the other entity participating in that relationship.`
    },
    
    {
        id: 57,
        category: "تحليل وتصميم النظم المحاسبية",
        difficulty: "hard", 
        question: `This relationship exists when the maximum cardinality of one entity in the relationship is one and the maximum cardinality for the other entity in the relationship is many.`,
        options: [`One-to-one`, `Many-to-many`, `One-to-many` , `Many-to-none (0)`],
        answer: `One-to-many`
    },
    
    {
        id: 58,
        category: "تحليل وتصميم النظم المحاسبية",
        difficulty: "hard", 
        question: `Which of the following is not a type of basic relationship between entities?`,
        options: [`One to one (1:1) relationship`, `Many to many (M:N) relationship`, `One to many (1:N) relationship` , `One to two (1:2) relationship`],
        answer: `One to two (1:2) relationship`
    },
    
    {
        id: 59,
        category: "تحليل وتصميم النظم المحاسبية",
        difficulty: "hard", 
        question: `The REA model:`,
        options: [`was designed specifically to assist the design of AIS.`, `identifies what entities should be in the AIS database`, `prescribes structural relationships among entities in the database.` , `All of the above.`],
        answer: `All of the above.`
    },
    
    {
        id: 60,
        category: "تطوير نظم المعلومات المحاسبية وفحصها",
        difficulty: "easy", 
        question: `Which of the following parties are important to the development and implementation of AIS?`,
        options: [`Management`, `Accountants`, `Information Systems Steering Committee` , `Project development team` , `All of the above`],
        answer: `All of the above`
    },
    
    {
        id: 61,
        category: "تطوير نظم المعلومات المحاسبية وفحصها",
        difficulty: "easy", 
        question: `Companies change their systems for various reasons. According to the text, which of the following is a reason?`,
        options: [`Technological changes.`, `Productivity changes.`, `Systems integration and replacement.` , `All of the above are key reasons.`],
        answer: `All of the above are key reasons.`
    },
    
    {
        id: 62,
        category: "تطوير نظم المعلومات المحاسبية وفحصها",
        difficulty: "easy", 
        question: `Which of the following is not a reason for resistance to change?`,
        options: [`If change is perceived as disruptive`, `Employees who had a previous bad experience with change`, `Lack of management support` , `Confidence and job security`],
        answer: `Confidence and job security`
    },
    
    {
        id: 63,
        category: "تطوير نظم المعلومات المحاسبية وفحصها",
        difficulty: "easy", 
        question: `Which of the following methods of evaluating capital investments utilizes present value techniques?`,
        options: [`The net present value method.`, `The payback method.`, `Internal rate of return.` , `Answers #1 and #3 only are correct.`],
        answer: `Answers #1 and #3 only are correct.`
    },
    
    {
        id: 64,
        category: "تطوير نظم المعلومات المحاسبية وفحصها",
        difficulty: "medium", 
        question: `Which of the following are strategies to determine AIS requirements?`,
        options: [`Ask users what they need.`, `Analyze existing systems.`, `Create a prototype.` , `Answers #1 and #2 only are correct.` , `Answers #1, #2, and #3 are correct.`],
        answer: `Answers #1, #2, and #3 are correct.`
    },
    
    {
        id: 65,
        category: "تطوير نظم المعلومات المحاسبية وفحصها",
        difficulty: "medium", 
        question: `A proposed project that does not consider the impact of the project on existing contractual obligations failed to consider which of following elements of systems feasibility?`,
        options: [`Economic.`, `Technical.` , `Legal` , `Scheduling`],
        answer: `Legal`
    },
    
    
    {
        id: 66,
        category: "تطوير نظم المعلومات المحاسبية وفحصها",
        difficulty: "medium", 
        question: `Which of the following is NOT an AIS objective?`,
        options: [`Auditability.` , `Complexity`, `Reliability.` , `Flexibility` ],
        answer: `Complexity`
    },
    
    {
        id: 66,
        category: "تطوير نظم المعلومات المحاسبية وفحصها",
        difficulty: "medium", 
        question: `Which of the following is a characteristic of a Gantt chart?`,
        options: [`It is a bar graph`, `Project activities are listed.` , `Shows progress to date for a particular activity.` , `All of the above.`],
        answer: `All of the above.`
    },
    
    {
        id: 67,
        category: "تطوير نظم المعلومات المحاسبية وفحصها",
        difficulty: "hard", 
        question: `Which of the following answers the question as to whether the planned system can be developed and implemented using existing technology?`,
        options: [`Economic feasibility`, `Legal feasibility` , `Technical feasibility` , `Operational feasibility` ],
        answer: `Technical feasibility`
    },
    
    {
        id: 68,
        category: "تطوير نظم المعلومات المحاسبية وفحصها",
        difficulty: "hard", 
        question: `Which of the following is NOT considered a conversion cost?`,
        options: [`Parallel operations`, `Systems testing` , `File and data conversions` , `System documentation`],
        answer: `System documentation`
    },
    
    {
        id: 69,
        category: "تطوير نظم المعلومات المحاسبية وفحصها",
        difficulty: "hard", 
        question: `How often should an AIS be monitored and minor modifications be made?`,
        options: [`Annually`, `Continuously` , `When technology changes` , `When the competition changes systems`],
        answer: `Continuously`
    },
    
    {
        id: 70,
        category: "محاسبة الشركات",
        difficulty: "hard", 
        question: `في 1/1/2022 تقرر تكوين شركة تضمان من شريكان احمد ومحمد يتقاسمون الارباح والخسائر بالتساوي قدم الشريك احمد كامل حصته برأس المال نقدا والبالغة 80000 دينار بينما الشريك محمد قدم حصته معدات بقيمة 50000 دينار مقيمة بالقيمة العادلة كما أن هناك التزاما على هذه المعدات بقيمة 10000 دينار لم يقم الشريك محمد بسدادها قبل تكوين الشركة وتم اعتبارها التزاما على الشركة بذلك سيكون راس المال الكلي للشركة هو :`,
        options: [`128000`, `130000` , `112000` , `122000` , `120000`],
        answer: `120000`
    },
    

    {
        id: 71,
        category: "محاسبة الشركات",
        difficulty: "hard", 
        question: `في 1/1/2022 تقرر تكوين شركة تضمان من شريكان كرم ومحمد يتقاسمون الارباح والخسائر بالتساوي براس مال 80000 سدد كرم حصته براس المال نقدا اما الشريك محمد سدد مبلغ 35000 دينار بحسب طريقة الشهرة فإن قيمة الشهرة`,
        options: [`7500`, `8000` , `2500` , `5000` ],
        answer: `5000`
    },
    


    { 
        id: 72,
        category: "محاسبة الشركات",
        difficulty: "easy", 
        question: `معاذ وخلف شركاء بشركة تضمان براس مال 
        معاذ 18000   خلف 22000 
في 4/1 تم رفع راس مال معاذ   6000 
8/1  تم تخفيض راس مال معاذ 12000
في 7/1 تم زيادة راس مال خلف 4000 
كان صافي الربح 100.000
المطلوب حسب راس المال اخر المدة`,
        options: [`معاذ 30000 خلف 70000`, `معاذ 45000 خلف 55000` , `معاذ 31570 خلف 68420` , `معاذ 40000 خلف 60000`],
        answer: `معاذ 31570 خلف 68420`
    },
    

    {
        id: 73,
        category: "محاسبة الشركات",
        difficulty: "hard", 
        question: `خالد ومحمد شركاء بشركة تضمان براس مال
        خالد 18000   محمد 22000 
        في 4/1 تم رفع راس مال خالد 6000 
        8/1 تم تخفيض راس مال خالد 12000
        في 7/1 تم زيادة راس مال محمد 4000 
        كان صافي الربح 100.000
        المطلوب حسب راس المال اول المدة`,
        options: [`خالد 30000 محمد 70000`, `خالد 45000 محمد 55000` , `خالد 25000 محمد 75000` , `خالد 40000 محمد 60000` ],
        answer: `خالد 25000 محمد 75000`
    },
    

    {
        id: 74,
        category: "محاسبة الشركات",
        difficulty: "medium", 
        question: `سائد ومصطفى وسميح شركاء في شركة تضامن بقتسمون الارباح والخسائر بنسبة 2:4:4 على التوالي في 2022/1/1 ظهرت أرصدة رؤوس اموال الشركة 
        40000 رأس مال سائد 
        50000 رأس مال مصطفى 
        25000 رأس مال سميح 
        قرر سائد الانسحاب مقابل 46000 نقدا 
        كم مجموع رأس مال الشركة قبل الانسحاب`,
        options: [`120000`, `125000` , `115000` , `130000` ],
        answer: `115000`
    },
    

    {
        id: 75,
        category: "محاسبة الشركات",
        difficulty: "easy", 
        question: `سائد ومصطفى وسميح شركاء في شركة تضامن بقتسمون الارباح والخسائر بنسبة 2:4:4 على التوالي في 2022/1/1 ظهرت أرصدة رؤوس اموال الشركة 
        40000 رأس مال سائد 
        50000 رأس مال مصطفى 
        25000 رأس مال سميح 
        قرر سائد الانسحاب مقابل 46000 نقدا 
        كم مجموع رأس مال الشركة بعد  الانسحاب`,
        options: [`120000`, `125000` , `115000` , `69000` ],
        answer: `69000`
    },
    

    {
        id: 76,
        category: "محاسبة الشركات",
        difficulty: "medium", 
        question: `سائد ومصطفى وسميح شركاء في شركة تضامن بقتسمون الارباح والخسائر بنسبة 2:4:4 على التوالي في 2022/1/1 ظهرت أرصدة رؤوس اموال الشركة 
        40000 رأس مال سائد 
        50000 رأس مال مصطفى 
        25000 رأس مال سميح 
        قرر سائد الانسحاب مقابل 46000 نقدا 
        كم مجموع رؤوس امول الشركة بعد  الانسحاب`,
        options: [`مصطفى 46000 سميح 23000`, `مصطفى 50000 سميح 19000` , `مصطفى 600000 سميح 9000` ],
        answer: `مصطفى 46000 سميح 23000`
    },
    


    {
        id: 77,
        category: "محاسبة الشركات",
        difficulty: "medium", 
        question: `في 2022/1/1 قرر الشريك رأفت الانسحاب من شركة تضامن التي تتكون بالإضافة اليه من حسين واسامة علماً بأن رؤوس اموال الشركاء والنسب موزعة كانت كالاتي 
        30000 دينار حصة رأفت 40% 
        24000 دينار حصة حسين 40% 
        16000 دينار حصة اسامة 20%  
        تقرر ان يتم الدفع للشريك رأفت مقابل انسحابه مبلغ 36000 دينار من أموال الشركة مقابل انسحابه  طريقة الشهرة 
        المطلوب كم مقدار الشهرة التي حصل عليها رأفت`,
        options: [`7000`, `8000` , `6000` , `5000` ],
        answer: `5000`
    },
    


    {
        id: 265,
        category: "محاسبة الشركات",
        difficulty: "medium", 
        question: `في 2022/1/1 قرر الشريك رأفت الانسحاب من شركة تضامن التي تتكون بالإضافة اليه من حسين واسامة علماً بأن رؤوس اموال الشركاء والنسب موزعة كانت كالاتي 
        30000 دينار حصة رأفت 40% 
        24000 دينار حصة حسين 40%
         16000دينار حصة اسامة 20% 
        تقرر ان يتم الدفع للشريك رأفت مقابل انسحابه مبلغ 36000 دينار من أموال الشركة مقابل انسحابه  طريقة الشهرة 
        المطلوب احسب مجموع رأس مال الشركة بعد الانسحاب`,
        options: [`50000`, `49000` , `51000` , `52000` ],
        answer: `49000`
    },
    

    {
        id: 79,
        category: "محاسبة الشركات",
        difficulty: "hard", 
        question: `في 2022/1/1 قرر الشريك رأفت الانسحاب من شركة تضامن التي تتكون بالإضافة اليه من حسين واسامة علماً بأن رؤوس اموال الشركاء والنسب موزعة كانت كالاتي 
        30000 دينار حصة رأفت 40% 
        24000 دينار حصة حسين 40%
         16000دينار حصة اسامة 20% 
        تقرر ان يتم الدفع للشريك رأفت مقابل انسحابه مبلغ 36000 دينار من أموال الشركة مقابل انسحابه  طريقة الشهرة 
        المطلوب احسب مجموع رأس مال الشركة بعد احتساب الشهرة وقبل انسحاب رأفت`,
        options: [`60000`, `70000` , `85000` , `50000` ],
        answer: `85000`
    },
    

    {
        id: 80,
        category: "محاسبة الشركات",
        difficulty: "hard", 
        question: `في 2022/1/1 قرر الشريك رأفت الانسحاب من شركة تضامن التي تتكون بالإضافة اليه من حسين واسامة علماً بأن رؤوس اموال الشركاء والنسب موزعة كانت كالاتي 
        30000 دينار حصة رأفت 40% 
        24000 دينار حصة حسين 40%
         16000دينار حصة اسامة 20% 
        تقرر ان يتم الدفع للشريك رأفت مقابل انسحابه مبلغ 36000 دينار من أموال الشركة مقابل انسحابه  طريقة الشهرة 
        المطلوب كم مقدار الشهرة كاملة`,
        options: [`7000`, `12000` , `112000` , `15000` , `13000`],
        answer: `15000`
    },
    

]

